Michael J. Drake Papers 1972-2008 (bulk 1973-1986)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Michael J. Drake Papers 1972-2008 (bulk 1973-1986)
MS 511
Drake, Michael J.
This collection is comprised of the professional papers of Michael J. Drake. The bulk of the material relates to his career as a researcher and professor in geochemistry, planetary sciences, and meteoritics at the University of Arizona. The majority of this collection predates 1994 when Dr. Drake became the director of the Lunar Planetary Laboratory and head of the Department of Planetary Sciences.
8.75 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://www.library.arizona.edu/speccoll
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on the collection
Biographical Note
Michael J. Drake was born on July 8, 1946 in Bristol, England. He received his Bachelor of Science Degree in Geology at Victoria University of Manchester, England, 1967 and earned his Ph.D. in Geology from the University of Oregon in 1972. Dr. Drake was a post-doctoral research associate at the Harvard Smithsonian Astrophysical Observatory in Cambridge, Massachusetts from 1972-1973. In 1973 he joined the University of Arizona faculty as an assistant professor in the Department of Planetary Sciences. He served as the associate director of Lunar Planetary Laboratory from 1978 through 1980 and became an associate professor of Planetary Sciences in 1978. In 1986 and 1987, Drake served as the Associate Dean of Science, and in 1994 he became the head of the Department of Planetary Sciences and the Director of the Lunar and Planetary Laboratory. He served in that capacity until his death in 2011.
Michael J. Drake was a leader in the field of extraterrestrial geology. He studied lunar rock samples, meteors and the moons of Saturn. His assisted with establishment of the University of Arizona Electron Microprobe Laboratory in 1974. He helped map the surface of Mars and was part of a NASA team that detected the presence of ice below the Martian surface in 2002.
Dr. Drake contributed to important space projects that gained international awareness for Lunar and Planetary Laboratory and the University of Arizona. These projects included the Cassini mission to explore Saturn, the Gamma-Ray Spectrometer onboard NASA's Mars Odyssey Orbiter, the High Resolution Imaging Science Experiment (HiRISE) camera onboard NASA's Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter, and the Phoenix Mars Lander.
Drake was the principal investigator for one of the most ambitious University of Arizona projects ever, OSIRIS-REx, the $800 million NASA mission designed to retrieve a sample of the near earth asteroid Bennu and return it to Earth. OSIRIS-REx is due to launch in 2016. It was the largest grant or contract the UA had ever received to date. The project was approved by NASA after 2 years of challenging work by Drake and only months before his death.
Dr. Michael J. Drake was a Regents Professor, the highest of faculty ranks reserved for full professors with exceptional achievements that have brought them national or international recognition.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into 10 series
Series I: Personal Files, 1972-1922
Series II: Correspondence, 1973-1986
Subseries 1: Professional correspondence.
Subseries 2: Organizational correspondence.
Series III: Proposals and Grants, 1972-1992
Subseries 1: Department of Energy (DOE)
Subseries 2: NASA
Subseries 3: National Science Foundation (NSF)
Subseroes 4: Other organization
Series IV: Professional Services, 1979-1985
Series V: Scholarship files, 1972-1991
Subseries 1: Presentations
Subseries 2: Articles
Subseries 3: Book Chapters
Series VI: Subject files, 1972-2008
Series VII: Instructional files, 1972-2008
Series VIII: College Class Work, 1965-1972
Series IX: Scientific Notebooks, 1968-1993
Series X: Picture Negatives, circa 1977-1980
Scope and Content Note
This collection is comprised of the professional papers of Michael J. Drake. Almost all of the materials relate to his career as a researcher and a professor in geochemistry and planetary sciences at the University of Arizona. The bulk of the papers date from 1973 to 1986 before he became the director of the Lunar Planetary Laboratory and head of the Department of Planetary Sciences in 1994. The largest series is the publications which is divided into four subseries; presentations, articles, books chapters, and general. Other items in the collection are his personal files, correspondences, proposals and grants, professional services, and a subject file.
Access Terms
Drake, Michael J., 1946-2011
University of Arizona--Department of Planetary Science--History.
University of Arizona--Lunar and Planetary Laboratory--History.
Mars Odyssey Orbiter.
OSIRIS-REX mission.
Microprobe analysis.
Lunar petrology.
Lunar geology.
Meteorites Research.
Asteroids Research.
Solar System Formation.
Cassini(Spacecraft).
Gamma-ray spectroscopy.
Mars (Planet).
Mars--Probes.
Saturn (Planet).
Saturn--Probes.
Moon--Origin.
United States. National Aeronautics and Space Administration.
Container List
- Series I: Personal, 1972-1982
  This series is arranged chronologically by year. It contains Dr. Drake's United States Visa application, his final thesis presentation along with the copy of the abstract, correspondence relating to his appointment to the Department Planetary Sciences faculty, a personal log, information regarding his 6 month sabbatical in 1981 at the University of Oxford, letters relating to Drake’s interest in the job of director of the School of Geophysical Sciences, Georgia Institute of Technology 1981-1982.
  - Visa, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ph.D. Thesis final oral presentation and copy of abstract, September 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Smithsonian Astrophysical Observatory appointment, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - University of Arizona, Department of Planetary Science appointment, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Personal log, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Sabbatical-University of Oxford, 1978-1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - School of Geophysical Sciences, Georgia Institute of Technology application, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Series II: Correspondence, 1973-1987
  This series contains professional and organizational correspondence including both incoming and outgoing mail. The series is divided into two subseries; the first is arranged by years and the second is arranged by title of the organization.
  - Subseries 1: Professional correspondence
    - 1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - January-February 1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - March-December 1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - January-September 1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - October-December 1975 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - January-June 1976 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - July-December 1976 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - January-April 1977 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - May-August 1977 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - September-December 1977 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - January-March 1978 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - April-July 1978 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - August-March 1978 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - January-March 1979 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - April-June 1979 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - July –September 1979 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - October-December 1979 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - January-March 1980 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - April-June 1980 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - July-September 1980 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - October-December 1980 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - January-June 1981 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - July-December 1981 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - June-March 1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - April-August 1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - September-December 1982 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - December 1983-May 1984 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - January-March 1985 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - April- September 1985 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - October-December 1985 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - January-June 1986 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - July 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 2: Organizational correspondence, 1974 -1982
    - International Union of Geodesy and Geophysics – IUGG, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) Lunar Sampling, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 14-16)
- Series III: Proposals and Grants - Dr. Drake’s involvement, 1972-1992.
  This series is arranged alphabetical by organization. The series is divided into four subseries: Department of Energy (DOE); NASA; National Science Foundation (NSF); Other Organizations..
  - Subseries 1: Department of Energy (DOE), 1981-1983
    - Partitioning of Radwaste Elements among Synroc minerals and related phases(not funded,), 1983 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Systematic experimental investigations of the partitioning of radwaste elements among minerals proposed for ceramic and synthetic roc immobilization (not funded,), 1981 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Subseries 2: NASA, 1974-1989
    - Acquisition of an electron microprobe, 1984-1989 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Acquisition of computer controlled SEMQ, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Evolution of Ree Patterns during Nebular Condensation, Accretion, and Lunar Differentiation, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Evolution of Ree and other trace element abundances during nebular condensation, accretion, and lunar differentiation, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Geochemical evolution of the moon and igneous meteorites, 1976-1979 (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
    - Geochemical evolution of the moon, igneous meteorites, and other terrestrial planetary bodies, 1979-1984 (Box 3, Folder 4-6)
    - Geochemistry of Petro graphically-Characterized Lithic Fragments and the Stratigraphy of Lunar Regolith, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Petrology and Geochemistry of Lunar Regolith: Model Calculations of Geochemical Evolution of Terrae and Mare Rocks., 1975 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Long duration exposure facility (LDEF), 1977-1980 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Meteoritic Basalts, 1980-1984 (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
    - Terrestrial analog studies of the relationships between Martian weathering products and primary igneous rocks, 1978-1982 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Trace Element Conference, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 3: National Science Foundation (NSF), 1974-1989
    - Collaborative research: San Carlos ultramafic nodules and alkali lavas, and the Central Arizona Mantle (not funded,), 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Electronic Microprobe, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Electronic Microprobe, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 16-17)
    - Experimental determination of trace elements partition coefficients at high water pressures, 1975-1982 (Box 3, Folder 18-19)
    - Experimental trace element geochemistry (not funded,), 1974 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Experimental trace element geochemistry, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - International conference on experimental Trace element geochemistry, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Petrogenesis of ultramafic nodules from Peridot Mesa, San Carlos, Arizona, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Subseries 4: Other Organizations, 1972-1992
    - Bi-national Science Foundation-Geochemical Evolution of the Lower Crust beneath Northern Israel, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Ira Kay Memorial Grant-Monte Carlo simulation of transport phenomena in silicate materials, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - National Association of Science (NAS). A Vax computer and computer network communication system, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Research Corporation-Geochemical consequences of equilibrium and fractionation during nebula condensation, planetary accretion, and subsequent large scale differentiation (not funded,), 1973 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - U.S. Forest Service- Seam proposal, 1972-1974 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - United States Nuclear Regulatory Commission. Systematic Experimental Investigation of the Partitioning of Radwaste among Mineral proposed for Ceramic and Synthetic Rock Immobilization, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - University of Arizona Foundation. Proposal to create 2 new laboratories for Geochemical and Nuclear Sciences, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - University of Arizona. Survey of interest in the use of Scanning Electron Microscope(SEM)/Electron Microprobe, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - W.M. Keck Foundation-Equipment for the development of combined SEM-EDS-IA Facility, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - W.M. Keck Foundation-Electron Microprobe/Stable Isotope Mass Spectrometer, 1989-1992 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Series 4: Professional service, 1979-2000.
  This series is arranged chronologically by year.
  - Associate Editor for the Proceedings of the 6th Lunar Science Conference, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Associate Editor for the Proceedings of the 7th Lunar Science Conference, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Associate Editor for the Proceedings of the 7th Lunar Science Conference, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Associate Editor for the Proceedings of the 9th Lunar Science Conference, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - NASA Lunar and Planetary Review Panel, 1979-1982 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Chairman of the panel from 1981-1982
  - Graduate Admissions Committee for Department of Planetary Studies, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Associate Editor for the Journal of Geophysical Union, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Faculty of Sciences Committee on Research Facilities, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Chemistry Department, University of Arizona Academic Program Review, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Member of the 1st Lunar Geoscience Orbiter Workshop -Minutes, January 21-22, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Member of the 2nd Lunar Geoscience Orbiter Workshop - Agenda, January 21-22, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Member of the 2nd Lunar Geoscience Orbiter Workshop - Minutes, March 27-28, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Series V: Scholarship files 1972-2005.
  This series is arranged chronologically and documents Dr. Drake’s writing career. It’s divided into four subseries; presentations, articles, book chapters.
  - Subseries 1: Presentations, 1972-1982
    - 53rd Meeting of American Geophysical Union ( AGU), Washington D.C.,- notes only, no paper, April 17-21, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - NATO Advanced Study Institute -Plagise feldspar – silicate liquid equilibria: trace element distribution and the calculation of temperatures and oxygen fugacites of terrestrial and lunar samples, July 11-20, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - International Conference on Distribution and Partition of Trace Elements and Origin of Volcanic Rocks - The experimentally determined Equilibrium distribution of SR, BA, Y, EU2+, and other REE between Plagioclase feldspar and coexisting magmatic silicate liquid., October 2-4,1972 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - AGU Fall Meeting - Geochemistry of Petrologically-Characterized Lithic Fragments from Apollo 16, December 10-14, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Fourth Annual Lunar Science Conference, March 5-8, 1973 Europium Anomaly: A Model for Prediction. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Fifth Lunar Science Conference, March 18-22, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      The Infrared reflectance spectra of Eucrites, Shergottites and Vesta.
      metro genesis on the Eucrite/Diogenite parent body as inferred from modeling cumulate formation
      Modeling of the Two Stage Evolution of REE Abundance Patterns in High-Ti Mare Basalt Liquids.
      Apollo 17 soil survey and Comparisons among non-Mare lithic fragments from Apollo and Luna 20 soils.
    - International Symposium on Geothermometry and Geobarometry, Plagioclase thermometry and barometry in igneous systems, October 5-10, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Sixth Lunar Science Conference, March 17-21, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      The Crystallization of Plagioclase Feldspar from Silicate Melt and Preliminary report on the Petrology.
      Preliminary Report on the Petrology and Geochemistry of Lithic fragments from the Apollo 15 deep drill-core.
    - Meteortical Society 38th Annual Meeting - Lunar Anorthosite Paradox in the light of mineral/melt Equilibria, July 28th-August 1st, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - The Conference on Origins of Mare Basalts - Modeling the two stage evolution of REE abundance patterns in high TI mare Basalt liquids and Mare Basalt Ree Evolution., November 17-19, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Seventh Lunar Science Conference -, March 15-19, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      Evolution of REE Abundances in High-Ti Mare Basalts: Problems with Total Melting and Equilibrium Partial Melting and a Possible Solution with Fractional Partial Melting
      Critical review of models for the evolution of high-ti mare basalts
    - NATO Advanced Study Institute - Plagioclase – Melt Equilibria, September 17-27, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Meteoritical Society 39th Annual Meeting - Geochemical Evolution of Eucrites: Composition of Eucrite parent body, October 18-21, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - AAS Division for Planetary Science 8th Annual Meeting - Possible Bulk Composition of Vesta: Evidence from Eucrites, January 19-22, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Eighth Lunar Science Conference - Thermal History of Lunar Magma Ocean, March 14-18, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Meteoritical Society 40th Annual Meeting - Metal Fractionation Patterns in the Bencubbin Meteorite: Possible evidence for fractional crystallization a parent body core, March 25-29, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - AAS Division for Planetary Sciences 9th Annual Meeting - Determination of the Bulk Composition of Terrestrial Planetary Bodies Utilizing Geochemical and Cosmo Chemical Methods: A Selective Review, October 26-30, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Conference on Luna 24, December 1-3, 1977 Magma types at the Luna 24 Site in Mare Crisium and the Luna 24 Landing Site from Kilometers to Micrometers. (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Ninth Lunar Science Conference, December 1-3, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      Magma types at the Luna 24 Site in Mare Crisium,
      Mare Crisium and the Luna 24 Landing Site from Kilometers to Micrometers
    - Ninth Lunar Science Conference, August 14-17, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 19)
      Geophysical and Geochemical Evolution of the Lunar Magma Ocean.
      The Case for at least three VLT Mare Magma types in the Luna 24 drill core.
      Experimental Investigations of Trace Element Fractionation in Iron Meteorites and Pyroxene/Melt Equilibria: An update,.
    - Meteoritical Society 41st Annual Meeting, Experimental investigations of trace element fractionation in Iron Meteorites., August 14-17, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - AAS Division for Planetary Sciences 10th Annual Meeting - Geochemical Evidence for possible core in the Eucrite Parent Body, October 30-November 3, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - AGU Fall Meeting - Henry’s Law Behavior of NI in an Olivine/Melt system, December 4-8, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Asteroids - Differentiation in Asteroidal-sized Bodies, March 6-10, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - 10th Lunar and Planetary Science Conferenc,e, March 19-23, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 24)
      Metal depletion in the Eucrites: Evidence for a Core or for a Heterogeneous Mantle in the Eucrite Parent Body Predicting Major Element Mineral/Melt Equilibria.
      Predicting Major Element Mineral/Melt Equilibria.
    - AGU Spring Meeting, May 28-June 1, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 25)
      Henry’s Law Behavior of NI in two Olivine/Melt systems and of SM in a Plagioclase/Melt System.
      Lunar Magma Ocean: Evolution, and Implications for possible Ancient Crusts of the Terrestrial planets-Invited Interview.
    - Gordon Research Conference - Crystal Liquid Equilibria, August 20-24, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Meteoritical Society 42nd Meeting - Metal content of the Eucrite parent body: Implications of Tungsten metal-Silicate partitioning experiments, September 3-7, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Conference on the Lunar Highlands Crust - On early global melting of the terrestrial planets(no abstract or paper,), November 14-16, 1979. (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - 11th Lunar and Planetary Science Conference, March 17-21, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 29)
      etro genesis on the Eucrite/Diogenite parent body as inferred from modeling cumulate formation.
    - Meteoritcal Society 43rd Annual Meeting - Formation of a Lunar Magma Ocean by Partial Melting, September 2-6, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - AAS Division of for Planetary Sciences - Argon and Nitrogen Systematics in Venus, Earth and Mars: Cosmo Chemical Implications., October 14-17, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - 12th Lunar and Planetary Science Conference, March 16-20, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 32)
      On the Differentiation of the Terrestrial Planets.
      Partitioning of Sm between Hibonite and Corundum and Silicate Melt.
    - NATO Advanced Study Institute - Differentiation of the Terrestrial Planets, March 23-April 3, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Meteoritical Society 44th Annual Meeting, August 17-21, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 34)
      Experimental Trace Element Partition Applied to Iron Meteorites.
      Constraints on the Origin of the Moon and the Metal content of the Eucrite parent body deduced from the Partition Behavior Tungsten.
    - Meeting of the Early Crustal Genesis Project(working meeting), November 13-17, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - 13th Lunar and Planetary Science Conference, March 15-19, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 36)
      Partitioning of Phosphorus between Metal and Silicate: Implications for the Moon and Eucrite Parent Body.
      Experimental Approach to Early Planetary Differentiation,
    - 14th Lunar and Planetary Science Conference, March 14-18, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 37)
      Geochemical constraints on the Origin of the Moon.
      Experiential determination of the portioning of Gallium between Metal and Silicate: Electron and Ion probability study.
      Meteorite from the Lunar Terrae: Preliminary petrology of ALHA 81005,9.
    - Meteoritical Society 46th Annual Meeting - Partitioning of Ree between metal and volatile/refractory element fractionation (no paper or abstract)., September 3-9, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - 15th Lunar and Planetary Conference, March 12-16, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 39)
      The SNC/Mars Connection: Geochemical Inconsistencies.
      Basaltic Volcanism on the Eurcrite Parent Body: Geochemistry and Mineral Chemistry of LHA80102.
      Basaltic Volcanism on the Eurcrite Parent Body: Petrology and Phase Equilibria of ALHA80102.
    - Conference on the Origin of the Moon - Origin of the Moon: Constraints from Volatile Elements, October 12-16, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - LPI Workshop on the Early Earth: The Interval from Accretion to the Older Achaean - A Model for Core formation in the Early Earth, April 23-25, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Meteoritical Society 47th Annual Meeting, July 30-August 2, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 42)
      Meteorites from Mars: Proofs, Problems and Paradoxes.
      Investigations concerning the Magmatic Iron Meteorites, Static vs. Dynamic Experiments.
      Core Formation in the Shergottite Parent Body (SPB).
    - 17th Lunar and Planetary Science Conference, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 43)
      Core formation in the Shergottite Parent Body and comparison with the Earth.
      Siderophile elements in planetary mantles and the origin of the moon
    - 18th Lunar and Planetary Science Conference Formation of the Moon and Terrestrial Planets: Constraints from V, Cr, and Mn Abundance in planetary mantles and from new planets, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Conference on the Composition of the Terrestrial Planets,Experimental Partitioning of Siderophile, Elements amongst Lithophile Phases: Preliminary results using Pixe Micro probe Analysis, September 5-6, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Subseries 2: Articles, circa 1960-2005
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1960’s-1970’s (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Luna 20, circa 1972 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Synthetic rare earth Silicate glass standards for electron microprobe analysis, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - A Unified approach to a problem: Petrological and geochemical studies of lithic fragments from Apollo 15 soils, circa 1973(1) (Box 5, Folder 49)